Dennis Kamau

Nairobi, Kenya

dennis@denmau.me



linkedin.com/in/denmau



+254 759 360 020



https://denmau.me

Summary

I am a Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in frontend and backend development. I harness the power of Machine Learning in my applications with TensorFlow and I am a TensorFlow-certified professional.

My skills span from building mobile applications with Flutter, Web applications with Angular is, and the backend with C# .NET Core or Diango.

I have experience with Java, Python, Vue.is, PHP, Containers (Docker) and PowerBi.

Experience

.NET Developer

The Jitu.com

Nov 2021 - Present (6 months +)

- Agile Methodology: Jira, Zendesk
- . NET, C#, Visual Basic, JavaScript, Apache Cordova
- · AWS, Ms Teams, Bitbucket, Ms SQL Server, Windows Server

Software Engineer

Startappz Limited

Oct 2021 - Nov 2021 (2 months)

- Deployed and Managed Linux servers on 'the cloud'.
- Developed and Maintained Deployment pipelines for various projects.
- Built consumer-facing Web and Mobile Applications.
- Built RESTful APIs with PHP and integrated them with Flutter mobile Applications.

Junior Machine Learning Engineer

Omdena

May 2021 - Nov 2021 (7 months)

- Reduced business expenses immensely by implementing computer vision with OpenCV.
- Built and optimized Machine Learning models with TensorFlow.
- Conceptualized APIs to serve ML models to edge devices.
- Collaborated with an agile remote team on Slack, with weekly meetings with the business owner.

Junior Web Developer (PHP and Flutter)

Startappz Limited

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021 (3 months)

- Developed bespoke Web applications with PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, and HTML/CSS.
- Developed Mobile applications with Flutter, often while collaborating with a UI/UX Designer.
- Developed beautiful UI for internal tools and automated backend tasks.

- · API integrations and Database management.
- · Helped with System Design.

zuri. Backend Developer Intern

Zuri Team, Inc.

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021 (4 months)

- Work on Full-Stack web projects with Python Django.
- Collaborate with other interns on projects over slack as a Backend Developer.
- Worked on a site that links drivers to a mechanic from any part of Nigeria!
- · Used tools such as Python, Django, and SQL.

Frontend Developer, BuildForSDG Challenge 2020

Andela

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 (5 months)

- Collaborated in an agile remote team to innovate on real-world, locally and relevant solutions focused on the Sustainable Development Goals(SDGs).
- worked on a team project to connect farmers to consumers.
- · Prepared visual presentations for team meetings.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and jQuery.

Education



Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2019 - May 2021

eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute

Full Stack Software Development

2021 - 2021

- PHP | JavaScript | HTML / CSS | MySQL
- Java Android Development
- · API Integrations and Firebase

Apps:Lab

21C Skills Training, Software Engineering

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

- Strong Computer Science principles and Data Structures & Algorithms.
- Learned the importance of Testing and how to go about it, and test automation.

Licenses & Certifications

DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization - DeepLearning.Al

TensorFlow Developer Certificate - TensorFlow Certificate Program